John Silberstein

Philadelphia, PA

Phone: 609-841-2068 <u>johnsilb@gmail.com</u>

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/johnsilb GitHub portfolio: https://github.com/johnsilb

Summary

Data Analytics professional who has a background in mission critical data reporting, providing visibility into project status, invoicing to customers and sales staff commissions and payroll. Experience working in a start-up environment where new tools data analytics tools were developed and implemented. Worked as a part of an ad-hoc team of data analysts to support each other in developing tools for use throughout the organization.

Technical Skills

Excel, VBasic, Python, Pandas, SciPy, NumPy, Matplotlib, Web Scraping, APIs, Tableau, Machine Learning, SQL, github

Projects

Web Scraping: https://github.com/johnsilb/web_scraping_mars.git

- The object of this project was to access a NASA webpage on Mars activity and then web scrape and process specific information.
- The tools used here included: splinter, BeautifulSoup, webdriver_manager, matplotlib and pandas.

Supervised Machine Learning: https://github.com/johnsilb/supervised-machine-learning-challenge.git

- For this project, it was required to read in data from a CSV file and then prepare the data for the model. The data was split in to test and training data, then the training data was run through the model and then the testing data was used to evaluate the accuracy of the model for use with this data set.
- Tools used include: numpy, pandas, pathlib, and sklearn

Big Data ETL: https://github.com/johnsilb/Big-Data-ETL.git

- Both of the Review datasets have been properly extracted, preprocessed, transformed into four different DataFrames, and then loaded into AWS.
- Tools used include: Spark, hadoop, and pyspark

Education

Penn LPS Data Analytics Boot Camp, Philadelphia, PA Certificate

An intensive 6 month long boot camp dedicated to Data Analytics and Data Visualization. Skills learned consist of Excel, VBasic, Python, Pandas, NumPy, SciPy, Matplotlib, SQL, SQLAlchemy, HTML, MongoDB, Pymongo, Flask, JavaScript, Leaflet, Tableau. Topics covered include Data cleaning, data analysis, APIs, SQL queries, Web Scraping, Interactive Web Visualizations and machine learning.

Temple University, Philadelphia, PA Economics and Marketing.

Bachelors of Business Administration

Bloomsburg University of Pennsylvania, Bloomsburg, PA

Information Processing major.

Curriculum was a computer major with a concentration in business. Learned COBOL, PL/1 and Basic and applied these programming languages in batch processing and data structures.

Relevant Experience

Sales Operations Manager Market Resource Partners, LLC

5/2004 – 12/2007 Philadelphia, PA

- Updated ad hoc Excel based payroll reporting system so that it could accommodate the growing company using Vbasic and other advanced spreadsheet techniques.
- Developed and maintained organizational reporting system that was used for client billing purposes and Account Executive bonus calculations.
- Worked with C-Level executives when new reporting was required as needed.
- Was part of the design and implantation team when we moved from the Excel based payroll system to an ADP system.

Additional Experience

Personal Trainer/Owner
Functional Fitness Philadelphia

1/2013 to Present Philadelphia, PA

Provided personal training services to clients. Used in-person continuing education to keep up-to-date on training techniques. Used my background in data analytics to build a tracking and billing system for clients.

Lecturer
SRH Heidelberg Fachhochschule

1/2009 to 5/2011 Heidelberg, Germany

Contract instructor teaching English in a business communications environment. Students were expected complete all course work using English with the goal that students would be able to communicate in English in any international business. Designed activity tracking tools, that were then shared and made available the Business English faculty.

Owner Computer & Networks, Inc.

1/2002-3/2004 Philadelphia, PA

Provided IT solutions, including hardware and software, to small and mid-sized businesses.

TeleAE

8/2001-12/2001

SAP Americas Newtown Square, PA

Worked with field sales personnel to provide qualified warm leads within the Oil/Gas/Chemical Sector.